ABRAHAM GOGULAMUDI

Whitefield, Bengaluru, KA 560066 Cell: 9945452856 - abrahamlincolng@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Meticulous embedded software leader brining 14 years of experience in embedded medical grade, automotive and digital infotainment product development field, with a focus on delivering innovative business solutions and successful track record of leading embedded software development projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages C, C++, VB, MFC, Qt, Python, Power Shell, Shell scripting,

Assembly, COM, DirectShow and OpenGL

Operation Systems Embedded Linux, Yocto, Windows CE 5/6/7/2013, Windows CE

Auto, Windows XP/XP Embedded, Windows 7/Windows

Embedded Standard 7, Windows Embedded 8, Windows 10 IoT,

VxWorks, Ubuntu, QNX and FreeRTOS.

Device Drivers Windows WDM, KMDF, UMDF, WSK, TDI driver frameworks,

Network NDIS 5.1/6.0, Virtual Device Drivers,

PCIe, USB, I2C, SPI, NAND/NOR Flash, Printer, Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, Audio and Video device drivers with DTM/WHQL compliance. Linux device drivers for Bluetooth, UART, SPI, I2C, accelerometer

and GPS.

Hardware and Software

Stacks

USB, PCI/PCIe, LVDS, VGA, I2C, I2S, SPI, NOR, NAND, SMBUS, SD/SDHC/SDXC, UART, Gyro, Barcode, Accelerometer and CMOS

Sensor.

Architectures Freescale: i.MX27/i.MX53/i.MX6, i.MX8.

TI: Davinci/Jacinto/Sitara.

Qualcomm: Snapdragon 410c.

Intel: x86/x64, Atom (Bay Trail)

Cypress: PSOC 4/5

Development Tools Visual Studio 6/2005/2008/2010/2015/2017, TI CCS, Eclipse,

PSoC Creator, GDB, Platform Builder, Atmel Studio and ADS.

Configuration

Management and DevOps

GIT, ClearCase, SVN, CVS, Perforce and TFS. Coverity, CPP Unit, Sonar, Doxygen and Jenkins.

Agile, SaFe and Waterfall.

Project Management Wireless Protocols Cyber Security

Wi-Fi 802.11, FIPS, Bluetooth, NFC and RFID. Secure Software Update, Boot, OSS, and CVE.

WORK HISTORY

04/2020 to Current

Staff Software Architect

GE Healthcare -Bangalore, Karnataka

- Architected Mural Connect Hub edge connectivity platform (IoMT) which serves various products across GE Healthcare.
- Architected Secure Embedded Linux OS distribution which caters multiple medical devices (10+) to address cyber security patching.
- Led strategic software platforming initiatives.

11/2015 to 04/2020

Product Owner

GE Healthcare – Bangalore, Karnataka

- Translated product manufacturing and service goals, feature concepts and manufacturing and service needs into prioritized product requirements and use cases.
 Translated multi-platform goals, feature concepts and customer needs into prioritized
- product requirements and use cases.
 Led product specification and application architectures which can run on multiple OSs.
- Led the Embedded platform development team that created Common Embedded Linux OS and application platform multiple products.
- Led the design and development for manufacturing, service, and development teams to ease of design, develop, manufacture and service.
- Created innovative and intuitive product features such as software updates and configuration backup OTA.
- Led communication with stakeholders regarding product goals and progress made.

04/2015 to 11/2015

Senior System Specialist

GE Healthcare – Bangalore, Karnataka

- Led bi-weekly Scrum planning meetings to develop team strategies and define project goals.
- Translated technical specifications into detailed product requirements.
- Coached and mentored 4 new staff members, including conducting performance reviews.
- Streamlined deployment process by developing continuous integration tools.
- Strengthened developmental methodologies by introducing a code quality document.
- Developed software components.

04/2014 to 03/2015

System Specialist

GE Healthcare – Bangalore, Karnataka

- Played key role in identifying next generation Hardware (iMX6/Sitara/Beagle-bone/Intel baytril) and Software (Windows CE/Embedded Linux/Windows Embedded Stranded/Yocto) platforms that resulted in multi-product platforming.
- Played key role in defined BSP specification and closely monitored the deliverable's from vendors.
- Played a key role in identifying multi-platform software frameworks.
- Played a key role in design and development of remote service framework.

08/2010 to 04/2014

Senior Design Engineer

GE Healthcare – Bangalore, Karnataka

- Developed Windows CE 6.0 BSP for freescale iMX27 based custom HW.
- Developed NAND Flash, USB Full Speed Host, SDHC 2.0, Battery, RTC, Watchdog and Fast Ethernet Controller drivers and tested with CETK
- Designed and developed custom USB based thermal writer, ECG acquisition device drivers and high-level application frameworks.
- Developed an innovative software-based emulator to help marketing and application developers to avoid HW dependency.
- Designed and developed MFC application.

11/2009 to 08/2010

Senior Engineer

Symphony Services – Bangalore, Karnataka

- Worked closely with other departmental peers to develop high availability solutions for mission-critical automotive applications.
- Designed and developed Radio Data Services protocol decoding and presentation for CAR infotainment application.

• MFC application development which controls DSP audio and video algorithms.

04/2007 to 10/2009

Staff Software Engineer

TESSOLVE EMBEDDED SYSTEMS – Bengaluru, KA

- Developed application software which demonstrates CMOS Sensor Features like Multi ROI functionalities. This software collects video frames and controls camera sensor over network
- Developed custom Windows CE 6.0 BSP for the custom Davinci board taking a Reference BSP.
- Developed WDM Device Driver, API library and GUI for PCle based analog to digital converter
- Developed NDIS based network driver for IPTV HD video receiver.
- Ported WDM USB network driver to KMDF network driver and also did debugging and testing driver for WHQL certification for window Vista
- Developed API library for various peripherals like GSM modem, Bluetooth, GNSS, Gyro Sensor on Magellan Promark-4 navigation system

Education	
2007	Diploma in Real Time Operating Systems: Embedded Systems Cranes Varsity - Embedded System Institute - Bengaluru, KA
2006	Bachelor of Engineering: Electronics and Instrumentation Engineering Bapatla Engineering College - Bapatla, AP
CERTIFICATIONS	
	Certified ScrumMaster
	Certified Product Owner
PATENTS	

PATIENT HEALTHCARE INTERACTION DEVICE AND METHODS FOR IMPLEMENTING THE SAME (us 20190198169 15/910686)